JACOB NEVITT

Motivated front-end developer with comprehensive training and practical expertise. Graduated from an award-winning coding bootcamp, refined skills at the UK's largest property rental website, and drove performance improvement at one of Canada's leading eCommerce companies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Article | May 2021-Feb 2024

- Developed website features using Vue to enhance overall UX and drive revenue growth.
- Liaised with designers, product managers, and the wider eCommerce team on design and product releases.
- Created a cross-sell component that helped generate \$30k in sales within the first month of implementation.
- Led a performance optimization initiative to implement strategic improvements and achieved measurable enhancements in loading times and overall UX.
- Added manual merchandising capability, enabling the team to identify featured products in Contentful CMS, and promote those products using Algolia.
- Contributed to the development of React-based extension apps for Contentful.
- Utilized GraphQL for efficient data querying, enhancing system communication
- Led monthly meetings to discuss industry trends including PWAs, Micro Frontends, and Wasm.
- Identified and repaired critical software bugs.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SpareRoom | Oct 2019-Oct 2020

- Contributed to the development and extension of RESTful APIs using TDD in Perl.
- Worked on both the front-end and back-end for the inhouse admin tool.
- Used MySQL to gather data and craft custom, reusable reports and mailshot criteria.
- Supported new payment processing systems project using the Stripe API.

ADDITIONAL WORK

Project Cargo Specialist CMA CGM | Oct 2017-May 2019

Vessel Operations Supervisor Mitsui OSK Lines | Jul 2015-May 2017

Vessel Cargo Planner Grimaldi Lines | Jul 2013-Jul 2015



jacobnevitt@gmail.com



(236) 885-4130



<u>linkedin.com/in/jacobnevitt</u>



github.com/jacobadam



jacobnevitt.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript TypeScript GraphQL HTML CSS

<u>Frameworks</u>

VueJS ReactJS

EDUCATION

Northcoders

May-Sept 2019

Full-stack coding course at an award-winning bootcamp based in Manchester, UK.

Leeds Beckett University

2009-2012

Upper Second Class Honours, Bachelor of Arts, Media Studies

INTERESTS

Soccer, cricket, cycling, running, hiking, chess, guitar, piano, film, and music.